Guide to the Yale School of Drama Production Notebooks of Master of Fine Arts Students
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale School of Drama production notebooks of Master of Fine Arts students
1974-1998
RU 309
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.5
(13 boxes)
The records consist of production notebooks of third-year Yale School of Drama students with concentrations in stage management. The production notebooks are one of three components making up the students' theses.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by year of graduation.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of production notebooks of third-year Yale School of Drama students with concentrations in stage management. The production notebooks are one of three components making up the students' theses.
Stage management; Yale School of Drama; Yale University -- Students
- Production notebooks of Master of Fine Arts students of the Yale School of Drama, 1974-1998; Accession 2001-A-003
  Scope and Contents
  Key:
  "Title of the Play"
  Author
  Director
  Stage Manager
  Drama Library Classification
  Date of Classification
  Volume number
  - "The Tubs" (Box 1)
    - Terrence McNally
    - Director: Anthony Holland
    - Stage Manager: Dia D. Thompson
    - Bt
    - +T372
    - 1974
    - v.1
  - "Shlemiel the First" (Box 1)
    - Isaac Bashevis Singer
    - Director: Isaiah Sheffer
    - Stage Manager: Peter Roberts
    - Bt
    - +R539
    - 1975
    - v. 1
  - "General Gorgeous" (Box 1)
    - Michael McClure
    - Director: Lawrence Kornfeld
    - Stage Manager: Julie Naber
    - Bt
    - +N105
    - 1976
    - v. 1
  - "Ivanov" (Box 1)
    - Anton Chechov
    - Director: Ron Daniels
    - Stage Manager: Shannon J. Sumpter
    - Bt
    - +Su6
    - 1977
    - v. 1
  - "The Durango Flash" (Box 1)
    - William Hauptman
    - Director: Kenneth Frankel
    - Stage Manager: Grant Collins
    - Bt
    - +C68
    - 1977
    - v. 1
  - "Wings" (Box 1)
    - Authur Kopit
    - Director: John Madden
    - Stage Manager: H. Lloyd Carbaugh
    - Bt
    - +C20
    - 1978
    - v. 1
  - "Measure for Measure" (Box 2)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: John Madden
    - Stage Manager: Neal Ann Stephens
    - Bt
    - +S39
    - 1980
    - v. 1
  - "Curse of the Starving Class" (Box 2)
    - Sam Shepard
    - Director: Tony Giordano
    - Stage Manager: Rik Kaye
    - Bt
    - +K
    - 1980
    - v. 1
  - "Mahagonny, A Chamber Version" (Box 2)
    - Bertolt Brecht & Kurt Weill
    - Director: Keith Hack
    - Stage Manager: Thomas R. Bruce
    - Bt
    - +B83
    - 1979
    - v. 1
  - "Buried Child" (Box 2)
    - Sam Shepard
    - Adrian Hall
    - Deborah Van Drimmeln
    - Bt
    - +V32
    - 1979
    - v. 1
  - "Terra Nova" (Box 2)
    - Ted Tally
    - Director: Travis S. Preston
    - Stage Manager: Thomas J. DiMauro
    - Bt
    - +D59
    - 1998
    - v. 1
  - "Hedda Gabler" (Box 3)
    - Hendrik Ibsen
    - Director: Lloyd Richards
    - Stage Manager: Pat Thomas
    - Bt
    - +T363
    - 1981
    - v. 1
  - "The Suicide"
  - Nicolai Erdman (Box 3)
    - Stage Manager: Margaret Guthrie Adai
    - Bt
    - +Ad18
    - 1981
    - v. 1
  - "The Magnificent Cuckold" (Box 3)
    - Fernand Crommelynck
    - D: Jonas Jurasas
    - Stage Manager: Judy Martel
    - Bt
    - +M351
    - 1981
    - v. 1
  - "Boesman and Lena" (Box 3)
    - Athol Fugard
    - D: Walton Jones
    - Stage Manager: Melissa Rick Cochran
    - Bt
    - +C63
    - 1981
    - v. 1
  - "Rip Van Winkle" or "The Works" (Box 3)
    - Richard Nelson
    - D: David Jones
    - Stage Manager: Dona Graham
    - Bt
    - +G75
    - 1982
    - v. 1 part 1
  - "Rip Van Winkle" or "The Works" (Box 3)
    - v. 1 part 2
  - "Hello and Good Bye" (Box 3)
    - Athol Fugard
    - D: Tony Giordano
    - Stage Manager: Russ Lori Rosensweig
    - Bt
    - +R73
    - 1983
    - v. 1
  - "Talley's Folly" (Box 4)
    - Lanford Wilson
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - Stage Manager: Chan Chandler
    - Bt
    - +Ch36
    - 1985
    - v. 1
  - "Richard II" (Box 4)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: David Hammond
    - Stage Manager: Linda-Jo Greenberg
    - Bt
    - +AG825
    - 1984
    - v. 1
  - "Playing in Local Bands" (Box 4)
    - Nancy Fales Garrett
    - Director: Bill Ludel
    - Stage Manager: William L. Lewis
    - Bt
    - +L589
    - 1983
    - v. 1
  - "About Face" (Box 4)
    - Dario Fo
    - Director: Andrei Belgrader
    - Stage Manager: Susan M. Ruocco
    - Bt
    - +R86
    - 1983
    - v. 1
  - "Much Ado About Nothing" (Box 4)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: Walt Jones
    - Stage Manager: Catherine Hazlehurst
    - Bt
    - +H325
    - 1983
    - v. 1
  - "A Child's Tale" (Box 4)
    - Carlo Capotorto
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - Stage Manager: William Lang
    - Bt
    - +L23
    - 1986
    - v. 1
  - "Othello" (Box 5)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - Stage Manager: Melodie Swanson
    - Bt
    - +Sw24
    - 1986
    - v. 1
  - "Little Eyole" (Box 5)
    - Hendrik Ibsen
    - Director: Travis Preston
    - Stage Manager: Heidi Schultz
    - Bt
    - +Sch77
    - 1986
    - v. 1
  - "A Play of Giants" (Box 5)
    - Wole Soyinka
    - Director: Wole Soyinka
    - Stage Manager: Kathleen Mellor
    - Bt
    - +M52
    - 1985
    - v. 1
  - "Faulkner's Bicycle" (Box 5)
    - Heather McDonald
    - Director: David Cambers
    - Stage Manager: Greg Markowski
    - Bt
    - +M347
    - 1988
    - v. 1
  - "Sarcophagus" (Box 6)
    - Vladimir Gubaryev
    - Director: David Chambers
    - Stage Manager: Greg Markowski
    - Bt
    - M347
    - 1988
    - v. 1
  - "Twelfth Night" (Box 6)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: Mark Rucker
    - Stage Manager: Donald Fried
    - Bt
    - F291
    - 1985
    - v. 1
  - "Twelfth Night" (Box 6)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Director: Mark Rucker
    - Stage Manager: Donald Fried
    - Bt
    - F291
    - 1985
    - v. 1
  - "The Memento" (Box 6)
    - Wakako Yamauchi
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - SM.: Gail Burns
    - Bt
    - +B94
    - 1987
    - v. 1 part 1
  - "The Memento" (Box 6)
    - v. 1 part 2
  - "Neapolitan Ghosts"(Questi Fantasmi!) (Box 6)
    - Eduardo De Filiddo
    - Director: David Chambers
    - Stage Manager: Clifford Warner
    - 1987
    - Bt
    - W238
    - 1987
    - v. 1
  - "Moon over Miami" (Box 7)
    - John Guare
    - Director: Andrei Belgrader
    - Stage Manager: Sandra Lea Williams
    - Bt
    - +W625
    - 1989
    - v. 1 part 1
  - "Moon over Miami" (Box 7)
    - v. 1 part 2
  - "Neddy" (Box 7)
    - Jeffrey Hatcher
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - Stage Manager: Dub Rusty
    - Bt
    - +R
    - 1988
    - v. 1
  - "The Beach" (Box 7)
    - Anthony Giardina
    - Director: Amy Staltz
    - Stage Manager: Julie Anne Moore
    - Bt
    - +M79
    - 1989
    - v. 1
  - "Bricklayers" (Box 7)
    - Elvira J. DiPaolo
    - Director: Walther Duglas
    - Stage Manager: Mary Sue Gregson
    - Bt
    - +G
    - 1989
    - v. 1
  - "Cobb" (Box 8)
    - Lee Blessing
    - Director: Lloyd Richards
    - Stage Manager: Kathleen Farrar
    - Bt
    - +F235
    - v. 1
  - "Miss Julie" (Box 8)
    - August Strinberg
    - Director: Dennis Scott
    - Stage Manager: Katheen O'Shea
    - Bt
    - +Os52
    - 1990
    - v. 1
  - "Summer and Smoke" (Box 8)
    - Tennessee Williams
    - Director: James Simpson
    - Stage Manager: James Mountcastle
    - Bt
    - +M875
    - 1990
    - v. 1
  - "Dinosaurs" (Box 8)
    - Doug Wright
    - Director: Rob Barron
    - Stage Manager: M.S. Strange
    - Bt
    - +St825
    - 1990
    - v. 1
  - "Rust and Ruin" (Box 8)
    - William Snowden
    - Director: Walton Jones
    - Stage Manager: Lori Anne Diggory
    - Bt
    - +D172
    - 1990
    - v. 1
  - "Pygmalion" (Box 9)
    - George Benard Shaw
    - Director: Donald Brown
    - SM.: Lori Anne Diggary
    - Bt
    - +D136
    - v. 1
  - "Largo Desolato" (Box 9)
    - Vaclav Havel
    - Trans.: Tom Stoppard
    - Gitta Honegger
    - Matthew A. Everett
    - Bt
    - +Ev5
    - 1991
    - v. 1
  - "A Moon over the Misbegotten" (Box 9)
    - Eugene O'Neill
    - Director: Lloyd Richards
    - Stage Manager: Karol Siegel
    - Bt
    - +Si3
    - 1991
    - v. 1
  - "Underground" (Box 9)
    - Ron Jenkins
    - Director: Adrian Hall
    - Stage Manager: Marjorie S. Goodsell
    - Bt
    - +G65
    - 1991
    - v. 1
  - "Democracy in America" (Box 9)
    - Colette Brooks
    - Director: Travis Preston
    - Stage Manager: Wendy Hope Bobbit
    - Bt
    - +B421
    - 1991
    - v. 1 part 1
  - "Democracy in America" (Box 9)
    - Technical Notes
    - v. 1 part 2
  - "Ohio State Murders" (Box 10)
    - Adrienne Kennedy
    - Director: Gerald Freedman
    - SM.: Renee Lutz
    - Bt
    - L98
    - 1991
    - v. 1
  - "Ties That Bind" (Box 10)
    - Walter Allen Bennett Jr.
    - Director: Jordan Corngold
    - Stage Manager: Neil Fox
    - 1990
  - "Hamlet" (Box 10)
    - W. Shakespeare
    - Stan Wojewodski Jr.
    - Laura Brown
    - Bt
    - +Br170
    - 1992
    - v. 1
  - "The Verge" or "The Geography of Yearning" (Box 10)
    - Erik Overmyer
    - Director: Stan Wojewodski Jr.
    - Stage Manager: Wendy Beaton
    - 1991
  - "My Children! My Africa!" (Box 10)
    - Athol Fugard
    - Director: Elisabeth Margid
    - Stage Manager: Debra Justice
    - Bt
    - +J87
    - 1992
    - v. 1
  - "Beauty Part" (Box 10)
    - S. J. Perelman
    - Director: Walt Jones
    - Stage Manager: Wendy Beaton
    - 1992 (Box 11)
  - "The Size of the World" (Box 11)
    - Chuck Evered
    - Director: Walt Jones
    - Stage Manager: Sally Plass
    - 1991
  - "The Death of the Last Black Man in the Whole Entire World" (Box 11)
    - Suzan-Lori Parks
    - Director: Liz Diamond
    - Stage Manager: Renee Mesard
    - Bt
    - +M56
    - 1992
    - v. 1
  - "Edward II" (Box 11)
    - Christopher Marlowe
    - Director: Stan Wojewodski Jr.
    - Stage Manager: Wendy Beaton
    - 1992
  - "Edward II" (Box 11)
    - Technical Notes
  - "The Colored Museum" (Box 11)
    - George C. Wolf
    - Director: Donald Douglas
    - Stage Manager: Regina Guggenheim
    - 1992
  - "The Cherry Orchard" (Box 11)
    - Anton Chechov
    - Director: Milos Mladenovic
    - Stage Manager: Myra Hope Bobbit
    - 1993
  - "St. Joan of the Stockyards" (Box 11)
    - Bertolt Brecht
    - Director: Liz Diamond
    - Stage Manager: Wendy Beaton
    - 1993
  - "St. Joan of the Stockyards" (Box 11)
    - Technical Notes
  - "First Lady" (Box 12)
    - Katherine Dayton & George S. Kaufman
    - Director: Stan Wojewodski Jr.
    - Nancy Elizabeth Vest
    - 1996
  - "Oleanna" (Box 12)
    - David Mamet
    - Director: Stan Wojewodski
    - Stage Manager: Terry T. Terzakis
    - 1993
  - "The American Play" (Box 12)
    - Suzan-Lori Parks
    - D: Liz Diamond
    - Stage Manager: Shannon Rhodes
    - 1994
    - v. 1
  - "The American Play" (Box 12)
    - v. 2
  - "Antigone in New York" (Box 12)
    - Janusz Gowacki
    - Director: Liz Diamond
    - Stage Manager: Marda Alcorn
    - 1994
    - v. 1
  - "Antigone in New York" (Box 12)
    - v. 2
  - "American Notes" (Box 12)
    - Len Jenkin
    - Director: Joanne Akalitas
    - Asst. Director: Liz Diamond
    - 1988
  - "Adventures of Amy Brock" (Box 13)
    - Julie McKee
    - D: Stan Wojewodski Jr.
    - Stage Manager: Meredith Scott Brittain
    - 1997
    - v.1 part 1
  - "Adventures of Amy Brock" (Box 13)
    - v. 1 part 2
  - "The Skin of our Teeth" (Box 13)
    - Thorton Wilder
    - Director: Liz Diamond
    - Stage Manager: J.P.Byrd
    - Bt
    - +B99
    - 1997
  - "The Cryptogram" (Box 13)
    - David Mamet
    - Director: Mark Rucker
    - Marjorie Craig Mitchell
    - Bt
    - +M68
    - 1997
  - "Candida" (Box 13)
    - George Bernard Shaw
    - Director: Stan Wojewdski Jr.
    - Stage Manager: Helen C. Bretherton
    - Bt
    - 0
    - 1998
    - v. 1